All right, we missed a little bit of the game there, but as I listen to this, maybe if you
want, you can go listen to it later, there's this really cool buildup that actually happens
within that piece.
The first few moments in that clip was kind of like each individual instrument that was
playing, just kind of quietly sort of wandering and looking for the melody and trying to figure
out where the melody was.
It's kind of, you know, like kind of not sure where it was going to go.
But then there's this moment when that huge ode to joy melody just like hits.
And every different voice, like the lowest basses, the soaring sopranos, the brass, the winds, the percussion,
it just all kind of hits at the same moment to produce this glorious melody that brings everything together.
And that score that was written by Beethoven and that's then conducted by the conductor,
it all just sort of comes together to produce the complete work.
And I think it's a beautiful thing.
By the way, has anyone ever performed that before?
Okay, yeah, a few of you all have here.
I was sharing this with the children's ministry teachers downstairs.
I asked them, and a couple of them were like, I played it on recorder.
And I was like, yeah, why doesn't the London Symphony have recorders?
But as we're looking at this here today, I think how we can approach this is that we have the score in front of us.
We have God's word that's laid out in front of us of what it is that God has designed for us to live out.
And Jesus is wanting to lead us into that, to show us the way forward.
And so I believe that God has actually given our church this vision of becoming a transcultural
spiritual family, reaching our neighbors, the nations, and the next generation.
And this is something that we're going to talk about today that we want to live out.
And again, we don't think this is like our good idea that we've come up with.
We're just trying to take what we see in the scriptures and live that out together as a
church family.
And if you're looking for a church today, then we hope maybe this will be helpful for you,
deciding, is this something that you would want to be a part of? And, you know, God works through
all different kinds of churches, and so maybe there's something else you'll feel called to.
But again, for those of us who are committed to this as our church home, we want to also remember
and kind of recommit to who God has called us to become. So we're going to be looking at a few
verses in Acts chapter 13, just verses 1 through 3. I'm going to go ahead and read this for us,
and we'll dig into it together here today. It says this,
We'll pause there and let me pray for us again as we've looked into God's word.
God, we invite you here to speak to us through your holy word.
We open up our hearts and our minds to you.
We ask, Lord, that you would speak to us today,
both personally and even together as the family of the church,
and show us, Lord, your will and your heart for us
that we get to live out together,
and help us, Lord, to take steps of faith in that together
as we start this new season as well.
Thank you for your faithfulness, God, over the past 30 years now.
God, we know that you have so much more in store for us,
so we look to you today, God, and we want to hear from you.
Thank you, God. In Jesus' name we pray. Amen.
Amen. Okay, so as we look into these verses,
into this chapter here today,
What I hope you'll notice is that there's something really special happening here in
the church in Antioch.
And this is the moment that, if you're familiar with the book of Acts and the New Testament,
you know, this is the moment where Paul's missionary journeys were kind of kicked off
that ended up reaching the whole Mediterranean world and beyond and became really a model
for God's mission to reach the nations that is continuing throughout the world today.
And I think that as we see that, it's no coincidence that that movement and those
things started happening at this church in Antioch. It's a very special place. And so we're
going to look at the church at Antioch today. And as we do, I want to just kind of point out and
process three specific things about this church that I think will help us and hopefully give us
just a better picture of what this vision is that God has called our church to together. And so
as we look at this church in Antioch, the first thing I think it's important for us to notice is
this is the first Gentile church. And if you're a Christian, you probably know what that word
Gentile means. If you're new to the faith or exploring things, like, what is that? I've never
heard that before. Gentile is what the Jewish people called anyone who wasn't Jewish. So if
you're part of any other people group or nation or whatever, if you're not a Jewish person, well,
you're a Gentile. But this is really significant here in this moment because the church didn't
start out including Gentiles. It started out primarily as a Jewish community. And so we see
a little bit of how this happens. If we rewind a couple chapters into Acts 11, how did this church
in Antioch gets started, we find out in Acts 11, it says, now those who were scattered because of
the persecution that arose over Stephen traveled as far as Phoenicia and Cyprus and Antioch,
speaking the word to no one except Jews. But there were some of them, men of Cyprus and Cyrene,
who on coming to Antioch spoke to the Hellenists also preaching the Lord Jesus. So again, something
really important is happening here. And just to really quickly retrace the story without getting
too much into it, if you rewind back to Acts chapter 2, what you'll see there is there's about
120 followers of Jesus. They're gathering together, they're praying, and as they're praying
together, the Holy Spirit falls upon them. They're empowered by the Holy Spirit to go out into the
city of Jerusalem and preach the gospel to the city miraculously in languages they didn't know
before. And this was a key moment because it was the Jewish festival of Pentecost, and people from
all over the region, from all different nations, speaking all different languages, had come there
for this festival. And so they're coming from all over the place, they're speaking different
languages, but it's significant to know they're most likely still Jewish in culture and in faith.
That's the reason they're there. They're there for a Jewish festival. And so earlier than that,
in Acts 1.8, Jesus had said, you're going to be my witnesses from Jerusalem to the ends of the
earth to every nation. But what happened after that day of Pentecost was the church pretty much
stayed in Jerusalem. They stayed there and continued to live out their faith as a community.
And so that happens until there's this persecution event that happens. A guy named Stephen goes out
into the street, and he preaches the gospel to the city, and some of the other Jewish citizens of
the city, they stone him, like they throw rocks at him to kill him and execute him. That happens,
And then a lot of the church members, they start running for their lives.
They're like, we need to get out of the city.
We need to go somewhere else.
And that brings us here to Acts 11 that I just read for you.
And what's happening there, it says, many of them spoke the word to no one except Jews.
And I think that's pretty normal.
I think for most people, to interact with people who are very much like ourselves is the most natural thing in the world.
We like to be around people that it's easy to interact with.
people who just seem familiar and who seem to do things the way we do and who maybe look like us
or maybe have similar cultural practices. That's very normal. And this is what they were doing. And
by the way, it's not at all bad to share the gospel with people who are like yourselves, okay? That's
great. But what we see happen here is something new. There were some of them that spoke to the
Hellenists. And what's a Hellenist? Is that someone whose name is Helen? No, that's somebody
who is Greek culturally. This is somebody who, again, the Jews would call Gentiles, someone who
is non-Jewish. And this is like a pivotal moment in the history of the church and the Christian
faith. And it's not at all clear what's going to happen after this when this moment comes around.
Because crossing over from something familiar to unfamiliar is a really difficult thing to do.
Some of us may have that experience. Can I show you a couple of quick examples of that just to
help us kind of get this. Some people have successfully crossed over from one thing to
the other really well, and it's actually pretty dramatic when it happens. A great example is
this actor named Bryan Cranston. You guys know him? Some of you know him from a show called
Malcolm in the Middle, right? Anyone watch Malcolm in the Middle? There's probably some older folks
here, okay? I don't see a lot of the younger folks here raising your hand. He played Hal, I think,
on Malcolm in the Middle. He's a goofy TV dad in a TV sitcom, okay? And he's like the goofiest guy
imaginable, and this is how he got started in his acting career. But then some of you, maybe a few
more of you know him, and it's one of the next roles he took, which was in Breaking Bad, where he
plays Heisenberg, right? Like, man, like, what a crossover. Like, this guy went from goofy TV dad
to drug kingpin. Like, it's, man, it's dramatic, right? Others have been able to do this well,
too. Sometimes it's just as, like, grow even in age. Like, many of you know Zendaya, right? You know
how she started out on the Disney Channel. I think this show was called Shake It Up. Anyone
grew up watching Shake It Up? It's not me, okay? But yeah, some of you, okay, some of you watched
Zendaya growing up, and you're like, man, yeah, she's a cute young girl, and she's like, she's
going for it on the Disney Channel. But then as she grew up, of course, we all know what she's doing
today. She's starring in like Dune and other stuff like that, much more like serious adult
dramatic kind of features. And like, man, she crossed over again really well from that child
star to now adult actress. Really cool to see that. Now, it doesn't always work out this well,
right? Not everyone crosses over well. For some people, they try and they fail. Like, many of you,
you're familiar with Snoop Dogg, right? Everyone knows who Snoop Dogg is. I mean, like, he's like,
like, OG hip-hop guy, right? But, like, Snoop Dogg, he started out in hip-hop, and then, I don't know
how many of you would remember, back in 2012, Snoop Dogg took a trip to Jamaica. And when Snoop
dog went to jamaica he discovered reggae and he came back from his trip to jamaica and he said i
am no longer snoop dog i am now snoop lion right and snoop lion is a reggae artist and he released
an album i think it was called reincarnated and in this album he uses his first reggae album okay so
but all the reggae fans they listened to his album and they just said snoop dog lion whatever
you sound like a tourist. This is horrible. And then all the hip-hop fans are like, we don't care
about reggae. And so Snoop Lion became Snoop Dogg again. It didn't work out. He returned back
to being Snoop Dogg again. All of this, I'm just trying to help us think about it. It's hard
to transition from something like maybe you didn't know before to something really new.
And here what we see happening is that the message of the gospel has now crossed over from being a
Jewish background faith and religious community to now being something that is being embraced by
people who are non-Jewish. And I think there's actually a beautiful truth there that I love.
And that truth is that the gospel of Jesus Christ connects with and speaks to every culture,
every language, every people group, every season of history, every background. The gospel connects
with us all. And the gospel is not restricted to one ethnic group, one culture, anything like that.
It actually translates and spreads and speaks to all cultures, which is a really beautiful thing.
And so we see this church in Antioch become the first Gentile church in this moment. And then
what happens as a result of that is they become a transcultural spiritual family, like we're going
to be talking about here today. And what does that mean? Well, I mean, first, I think it's
important for us to recognize here. It's an opportunity to reflect on the fact that church
is not primarily a building or a meeting or a social club or something like that. Church is
the family of God. That's what the church is intended to be, is the family of God. And in
Antioch, we see people from a lot of different backgrounds forming this family together. And
there are several people all mentioned in this passage. And when you start to realize the
different backgrounds they'll come from, you realize, wow, this is really significant. Here's
a map of some of the different places that are referenced in this passage here today. You can
hopefully see some of those different places as I talk through it. The first person mentioned here
is Barnabas, and he's a Levite from Cyprus. So a Levite means he's from a Jewish background. He's
part of like the Jewish, like the group of people among the Jews who would serve in the temple. So
he's like a minister in the temple. But we also find out that he's from Cyprus. He is from this
island in the Mediterranean. He's not from Israel. He's not from the land of Judah. And then you've
got people like Simeon. It says Simeon called Niger. What does that mean? That's literally like
Simeon the black guy. That's what that means. Niger means black. And so this is probably someone from
like sub-Saharan Africa. He's actually off the southern end of this map that you're looking at
right here. And then you've got Lucius from Cyrene. So he's from Libya. He's a North African.
And then you've got Menaean, he's a lifelong friend.
That word that's translated lifelong friend, it means intimate friend or foster brother of Herod Antipas.
Oh, thanks. Cool. Thanks, Dave.
Yeah, so they're all there.
And this is like Herod Antipas, that guy, that's who killed John the Baptist.
Okay, so now there's some tension getting introduced here.
Somebody who was really loved by the early Christian community is somebody like John the Baptist.
He was actually killed by this guy's foster brother.
That's some tension.
And then Saul brings a lot more in.
He's a Jew from the tribe of Benjamin, but he was born in the Roman city of Tarsus.
And we find out he's kind of ethnically ambiguous.
He was mistaken for an Egyptian.
So you have a friend like that, you're like, I can't quite tell.
Like, where are you from?
Like, you know, not sure.
Like, that's Paul.
He's no one sure.
You Jewish?
You Egyptian?
where are you? And so he's coming in, and this whole community here, what I want us to realize
is this is much more than just a diverse community. It's not, like, this isn't a community that just
has good diverse demographics. This is a story of redemption playing out in front of our eyes,
because think about this with me for a second. Like, do you remember, and we just read these
verses a few minutes ago, do you remember how this church in Antioch got started? Why did people
go up there in the first place? Well, people went up there because of the persecution that happened
with this guy, Stephen, right? Stephen, he was one of the leaders in the early church, one of the first,
people would consider him like one of the first deacons in the church. He went out into the city,
he's proclaiming the gospel as he's doing so, that offended the residents of the city,
and they decide to stone him to death, and somebody was there actually pronouncing the
guilty verdict and giving permission to actually execute Stephen. And who is that person? That was
Saul, or later known as Paul. And so when you see this group of people together, you have to realize
people like Lucius or Simeon, mentioned in this passage, they had to run for their lives because
of Paul. They might have even watched their friend get executed at that time. So they run for their
lives. They end up in the city of Antioch, and later on, Paul, Saul shows up, and now they're
part of the same church family. And I, like, think about this. Like, what would that first meeting
have been like? Lucius and Simeon and all them, they're like praying, worshiping together, and in
walks Saul. Just like, hey guys, sorry I executed your friend. Man, what is that? And when you think
about that, you realize this is the power of the gospel of Jesus Christ. That because Jesus died
on the cross for us, shed his blood for us, for our forgiveness, for our redemption, for our
cleansing, for our healing, there's now no sin that cannot be forgiven and no pain that cannot be
healed and restored. God's race is in fact so powerful that someone who actually watched his
friend executed for his faith can now worship and pray side by someone, side by side with someone
who actually ordered that execution. That's a powerful truth. And for many of us, that feels
impossible. Like, how could that possibly happen? And I just want to say this too. I think for a lot
of people, a lot of people's experience is, I come into the church, I come into these meetings,
these gatherings, this organization, and I wonder if I could belong here. In fact, I wonder
if people knew who I really was, if people knew what I do behind closed doors, if people knew
what was in my past, if people knew how far I'd gone from God, if people knew that, would they
really accept me? Could I actually be part of this community? Many of us wonder that, and we actually
fear that. Could I be loved and accepted within this community? This shows us here, this is
actually what God wants. It's all of us. That's true for all of us. All of us have sinned and fall
short of the glory of God. All of us have run away from God. All of us have done things that we'd be
embarrassed if other people found out about, if not outright ashamed. And yet, the power of the
gospel here is that we can all be welcomed into the family of God. This is truly miraculous,
but it's also really, really important.
Because when we think about that great commission
that Jesus has called us to,
to go make disciples of all nations,
well, how can we bring the gospel to others
if we are not living out that truth ourselves?
If we aren't just talking about it,
but living it in love and forgiveness and grace
and patience toward one another.
And more than that, it's gonna be really hard
to take the gospel to the nations around us
if we can't even cross cultural boundaries
right here where we are.
and I think that also says something
to those in the world around us
who are kind of looking at us
and wondering what it is that we're about.
I'll share a quick story with you here.
This is from a long time ago
and I don't remember exactly when
but it's a long time ago in the history of our church
and we were doing some kind of outreach service activity
around the community here in Ann Arbor at the time.
We were like just serving some area,
I think a neighborhood here in Ann Arbor
and a bunch of us from our church were there
and were serving and just doing things
to help this community.
and it was going really well. We were there, you know, for a good chunk of time, several hours,
and as it was getting toward the end of the event, somebody said something to me that I think really
stuck out to me. In order to understand this, I just want to briefly acknowledge something that
maybe not all of us realize, but I think it's just helpful, is our church is majority Pan-Asian.
Okay, if you didn't see that yet, like, I didn't realize. Wait, what? No, okay, so we're majority
Pan-Asian right now, and we always have been. In fact, back at this time, we're even more so.
Majority Pan-Asian ethnic groups within our church. And so we're there. We're all serving
in this community. And I was talking with one of the members of the community as we got to the end
of the day. We're finishing things up. And we were just talking. We were just chatting, talking
about life, getting to know each other. And then as we were talking, he just kind of looked out at
everybody who was serving and doing things. And he said something to me. He said,
man, those Asian folks sure are nice.
I was like, okay.
But I kind of suffered.
I was trying to figure out how do I sensitively say this.
I think I said something like,
they're not just Asian, they're Christian.
Because I think what I realized happened there,
we wanted to be there to represent Christ.
We wanted to be there to show the love of Christ
to our city, to this neighborhood.
We wanted to be there to show people that God loves them.
and that God has a purpose for them, and that Jesus came to save them.
We wanted people to see Jesus, but what, at least for this man,
what he actually saw was just an ethnic group, a common ethnicity.
And so what we wanted attributed to Christ,
he instead attributed to an ethnic group, a culture.
And that stuck out to me at that moment.
I mean, partly that made me feel a little weird.
But, you know, as I thought about that,
I realized this is why actually this picture of the church we see in Antioch is really important.
You know, something else significant happened at Antioch.
If you look in chapter 11, verse 26, it says,
In Antioch, the disciples were first called Christians.
And do you know why that happened?
It wasn't because they were just especially sincere in their faith more than anybody else.
Prior to that time, anyone who was a follower of Jesus would have been called a Jewish follower of the way.
That's what they would have been called, a follower of the way, a Jewish person.
But here now, for the first time, they couldn't peg this group as any one ethnic group.
They couldn't say, oh, those are the Phoenicians over there.
Oh, yeah, those are the Syrians over there.
Oh, yeah, those are the Hittites over there.
Those are whoever.
They couldn't put it on any one ethnic group of people,
so they had to say, what's their common denominator?
What do they have in common?
Because it's not their ethnicity, it's not their culture,
it's not their background.
Maybe it's not even their language.
Maybe it's not the way they dress.
Maybe it's not anything else.
The sole thing they had in common was that they were following Jesus.
And so what can we do but call them Christian?
What can we do but identify them that way?
And I want to acknowledge as we look at this here
and think about what that means,
This is really hard.
What we're talking about, being a transcultural spiritual family,
it's really, really hard.
It's not easy at all.
But this, I think, is something that goes beyond demographics or statistics.
It's not about those things.
At this level, it's about friendship.
It's about trust.
It's about partnership.
It's about connecting with people at a deep level,
not just sitting side by side like this,
but really being in each other's lives and learning to trust one another.
And that's a really difficult thing to do.
And so that's why even I've been using that word transculture,
but let me just define it real quick.
The way we use that is to mean a decision to be uncomfortable
and cross cultural boundaries for the sake of the gospel.
That's what we mean when we use that word.
It's not just about demographics.
It's a decision we make to say,
I'm not going to just stay in my comfort zone.
I'm going to go outside of that, beyond that,
to connect with someone who's different from myself for the sake of the gospel.
And again, this is not our good idea as a church or something.
Paul writes about this in 1 Corinthians 9.22.
He says, I have become all things to all people that by all means I might save some.
This is what we're trying to live out.
This is what we see happening.
This is what we want to live and be and breathe together.
And again, this is hard.
Like, some of you, maybe you're curious about this and you want to dig into it a little bit more.
Again, it's not just about, like, foods you eat or, like, different cultural things.
But, like, it gets to a lot of deep levels.
If you want to look into it, there's a woman named Erin Meyer.
She actually studied this in a business context and wrote a book about it called The Culture Map.
And here's some different dimensions of culture that she talks about.
And we're not going to go through these.
I just want to throw it up there just for us to think about.
As you look at this and think about it, like, wow, okay.
Like, there are so many different ways we can miss each other.
It can be anything from, like, very practical things.
Like, one person shows up on time because they see time as very precise.
To another person shows up, like, pretty late because they're like, oh, yeah, scheduling.
that's very flexible, that's very relational, I just show up, you know, whenever. We can miss each
other on these things, and it can get to very deep levels, and some of you may want to look into this
a little bit more. She's talking about it in a business context, so she's not even getting into
things like how that affects our sense of social identity, or how we morally process things. There's
much more than this that we can even miss each other on, and because of that, it's really, really
difficult. And in fact, what I would want to let you know up front, if you're like, man, do I want
to be part of this church? Do I want to be part of this kind of transcultural community? It's
really hard, and you'll probably experience things like frustration or disappointment or
discouragement. And I can share that even personally. Like today, there's still times I sometimes feel
like an outsider. I'm a lead pastor. And even when I first became a Christian, here within this
church, this is my only church I've ever been part of. And back my freshman year, when I came to know
Christ and joined this community, I was trying to get to know people, and I always had great
relationships with older people in the church who really cared for me, took me under their wing,
what I really struggled with was peer friendships. I really struggled with finding people my age,
like my class, people who are like peers to me that I could be close friends with. It took a long
time, and it was very frustrating and very difficult. Some of you may experience that.
There are many times I actually wanted to leave and go somewhere else, but as I prayed through it,
I felt like God was calling me here because I felt these things were important. And so I struggled
through that. And each of us is going to have to struggle through that in our own way. But the
challenge here is if we want to reach the nations with the gospel, we need to learn to build those
kinds of transcultural relationships. And I think in today's globally connected world, that becomes
more important and more valuable than it ever has been before. So this is the kind of community that
we see in the church there in Antioch. And the third thing, last thing that we notice about this
church is that they were led and empowered by the Holy Spirit. I noticed that in these few verses
they're worshiping together, they're fasting together, they're praying together. And I think
it's really interesting that this is actually where they're finding their unity. They're not
finding their unity in something else, like, oh, we all happen to play soccer together, or we all
happen to like this one kind of ethnic cuisine, or we all happen to wear the same kind of clothes,
the same fashion. They're not finding their unity in anything else, but in that relationship with
God. And I shared with you earlier that orchestra example, but here's maybe another one that ties
into that same kind of thought a little bit, a quote from A.W. Tozer. He says, has it ever occurred
to you that 100 pianos, all tuned to the same fork, are automatically tuned to each other? They are of
one accord by being tuned, not to each other, but to another standard to which each one must
individually bow. So 100
worshipers met together, each
one looking away to Christ,
are in heart nearer to each other
than they could possibly be
were they to become unity conscious
and turn their eyes away from God
to strive for closer fellowship.
You realize, I think
this is what it comes down to.
Being that transcultural spiritual family,
it's not just shooting for demographic
numbers or anything like that. It's really
about saying we want to be united in
Christ over anything else. Where do we find that? We find that as we worship together, as we pray
side by side and for one another, as we hunger after God together, as we live out our faith and
community focused on Christ, he brings us together. And that's what we see in this church.
They're using their spiritual gifts to minister to each other. They're receiving guidance from
the Holy Spirit. They're sending people out to reach the nations with the gospel. And notice
that. This is really key as we kind of wrap up here today. Notice these couple things. Verse 3,
it says, after fasting and praying, they laid their hands on them and sent them off. They laid their
hands on them and sent them off. If you just look one verse further, if you have your Bibles open,
notice the beginning of verse 4. It says, so being sent out by the Holy Spirit. I don't know if you
ever noticed that before. They laid their hands on them and sent them off. So being sent out by the
Holy Spirit. Isn't that interesting? Which one is doing the sending? Who is it that's sending them
out? Who is it that's sending out this team to go and bring the gospel to the nations? Well, I think
what we see happening here is that actually what God is doing, the people are actually joining in.
And this is important because I think for many of us, we ask the question, what does God want me to
do? God, what do you want me to do? God, what's your will for my life? God, what do you want me
to do? We ask that question, and it's not a bad question, but I think the better question to ask
that maybe we can think about here is, God, what are you doing because I want to join you?
God, what are you doing because I want to join what you're doing? Not God, what's your will for
my life? God, what do you want me to do? But God, what are you doing because I want to join in what
you're doing? And I think that's what's happening here. As the church, they're united in worship,
in prayer, in seeking God. They realize the heart of God is to reach the nations, the Holy Spirit,
is speaking to them, saying, I want you to send people out to go to the nations. It's what God
is doing first. And then the people, they're joining in what it is that God is doing. And I
share that because here today, we're sharing this vision of what I believe God is doing and wants
to do within our church. That vision of becoming a transcultural spiritual family, reaching our
neighbors, the nations, and the next generation. And if we think about that here today and say,
God, what is it that you're doing?
God, is this what you're doing?
Then maybe that will lead us
to recommit ourselves to this and say,
yes, God, we wanna do this together.
Even when we talk about reaching our neighbors,
the nations, the next generation,
well, Jesus, you're calling us to be the salt
and the light and love our neighbors as ourselves
with people right around us.
And those might be people that are very much like us.
They might be people that are
from the same ethnic background.
They might be people who are studying the same major.
They might be people who are in the same workplace
or the same neighborhood
or raising their kids in the same schools.
Praise God for that.
But also then we're challenged to reach the nations
here in our campus and our city,
here in this area where people come from around the world.
Even if we go to the nations,
we're called to be part of that.
And Jesus has also called us
to reach the next generation coming after us,
whether that's kids or youth or college students
or whoever that might be,
knowing there are new generations coming up after us
that we are called to reach and disciple.
And something I often think about
is that here where we are, we have the privilege and opportunity to be part of God's mission
in a way that many people in the world never get to be part of. I know right now believers who are
living in Syria who have come to know Christ from a Muslim background and they have to live out their
faith very secretly, very underground for fear of persecution against them. They don't never get to
live out their faith the way that you and I do. I've met people deep in the Amazon jungle in Peru
and they live in a village way back in the jungle
and they will probably never see the outside world
or maybe even see someone from another tribe.
They will never get to live out their faith
the way that we have the privilege to do.
We are here in this place,
on this campus in Ann Arbor, Michigan
and we get to study and work and live
and raise our families and hang out with people
in a place where the nations gather
and where the next generation comes
to prepare for the future.
And so as we start this new season of ministry
this year ahead, let's commit together
to becoming this kind of transcultural spiritual family
and joining God in the work he is gathering,
he is doing to gather all people to himself.
That's what we want to do as we finish up this time.
And a couple next steps I have for us here,
because this can all be very just theoretical ideas.
Can I give you some things
that I hope will be a little bit more practical?
We as a church will try to do different things together
to live this out corporately
in our gatherings and events and stuff like that.
But a lot of this comes down
to each one of us taking ownership of this calling
and living it out together.
And so what could that look like?
The first thing I would encourage you with
is practice living out the gospel in community.
Practice living out the gospel in community.
Again, we can't bring to somebody else
what we are not living in and experiencing ourselves.
And this is what we really pray will happen
within our life group communities,
these biblical communities of grace and truth
that we wanna belong in.
And if you haven't signed up for a life group yet,
you can do it with that link on the screen,
hmcc.tech slash LG.
We would love for you to get involved.
And when you get involved in life group,
it will not be a perfect community.
Turn to someone next to you and say, it won't be perfect.
When you join that community, it is quite possible, maybe even likely,
that in that community, somebody might disappoint you.
There might be somebody that you were hoping would come through for you in a certain way,
and they might let you down.
At the same time, you might be there in a life group meeting,
and you realize, oh my gosh, I just said something,
and it really offended that person.
I didn't mean it, but I accidentally offended that person.
Man, what am I going to do?
Those things might happen in life group
because we're people and that's what people do.
But in that community, we are not without hope
because in that community,
we actually have the message of the gospel
that we can share with each other
that because Christ died on the cross for us,
well, I can ask for forgiveness and I can be forgiven
and I can offer forgiveness to others.
We can live that out together
and see that Christ is actually bigger
than the ways we disappoint each other
or offend each other or anything else like that.
Let's learn to live that out together.
Second thing I would encourage us with
is to explore and celebrate other cultures.
Explore and celebrate other cultures.
This is something that I think it's really great
just to be curious.
And that might mean like asking someone,
you know, what's something that you love about your culture?
Ask that to somebody from a different cultural background
than you are.
What's something you love about your culture?
And then maybe they'll share with you
and you can share with them and you can learn
and maybe even experience that together.
I love that.
Like, I mean, I think from my culture,
there's something I grew up with
is this Dutch pastry, because I'm half Dutch, and the other half, I'm not sure what I am, but I'm
half Dutch. And there's this Dutch pastry called banquette. It's made with almond paste and like a
nice flaky crust pastry. I love it. Everyone I've shared it with that is not like from a European
ethnic background does not like it, okay? But I love it. But so then I look at our church, and I'm
like, man, I love it because my ethnic background, we do not have a lot of flavor. We're not so good
at that. And I'm like, man, praise God he put me in a church with some flavor. Let's share that
flavor, okay? Like, let's
enjoy that together, okay? And so this
is where, like, share with each other.
Share with each other. And
let's be a community that celebrates
that together rather than being, like,
one thing I want to say, this means being transcultural
as a church does not mean that we just sort of
flatten all culture and become really bland.
Okay? It means we, the
cultures that are here, we celebrate.
And maybe we do pay attention, like, man,
if there's, like, a majority here and there's one person
that's a little outsider, maybe we actually pay special
attention to make sure that that person's culture
also gets invited and celebrated and shared, but we want to lift up that celebration of different
cultures, not try to flatten them all out, and just share that with those around you, and then lastly,
the third thing is just discover your role in God's family. If you're here within our church
community, I think it's because God has a purpose for you to be here, and for each of us, that's
going to be different. We're going to talk about this some more next week and throughout the coming
year. I think God has a role and a purpose for each one of us, and for some of you, maybe you're
the encourager that somebody else needs. For someone else, maybe you're the prayer warrior
who goes into spiritual battle for the sake of others and for God's kingdom. Maybe you're the
person that loves to serve. Maybe you're the person with the great listening ear. Maybe you're
the person who loves to study and explain God's word. Maybe you're the person who loves to worship.
All kinds of things. We need all of that. Just like that symphony we listened to earlier,
every instrument, every voice, every section, all of it is all needed to become this kind of church
that really displays the gospel to the world. So let's explore that, discover that, and then live
that out together, because the body of Christ needs each one of us to discover our part and
live that out in this family. Could you turn to somebody next to you and say, you're an important
part of this family? Amen. We're going to spend some time in response here today. If I can invite
us to stand together. As we stand here this morning, if you'll just bow your head with me
for a moment. This is a, as we hear God's word and look into it together, we want to respond
with prayer, with worship, saying, God, I don't just want to hear and go on my way. God, I want to
build a relationship with you. I want to interact with you. I want to process with you the things
that you're speaking to me about. And in this moment, just be here with the Lord for a moment.
And even as we're just standing here, I don't know, maybe there's probably all different kinds
the things going through all of our minds. Maybe for some of us, it's excitement. Maybe for some
of us, it's anxiousness or fear. Maybe for some of us, it's just like, I want to go to lunch.
And I don't know what it is for you. But in this moment, I believe God has a reason for each of us
to be here this morning. And as we gather in this place and think about that vision, that calling that
God has for our church that he wants to lead us into, I know what the Lord desires for us is
actually not to focus on ourselves, but actually to focus on him. Because again, what all of this
is about is not us trying to make something of ourselves, us trying to figure out all the details
and all the dynamics of it. That's not what it's about. It's actually about focusing on God,
trusting in Jesus, following the leading of his Holy Spirit, living that out in response to who
God is and what he's done. And so here, whatever it is that's on your heart, maybe you feel like
God is speaking to you about something specific today, meeting you in an area of discouragement or
something that's got you down. Maybe it's excitement. Maybe it's like, God, I don't
know. I'm confused. I don't know what to do. Can we bring those things to the Lord in this moment?
And we want to bring those things to the Lord in worship. So again, that church in Antioch,
they didn't find their unity, they didn't find their direction, they didn't find their purpose
in focusing on themselves and what they could do. They found that unity in focusing on the Lord
and looking up to who God is and reflecting on the gospel of Jesus Christ and hungering and thirsting
after him together. So that's what we want to do as we begin this time of response. And the worship
team is going to lead us in worship here together. And as we worship, if you want to just join in
worship and be united in that together with all your heart, then do that. And if you feel like you
need to just maybe spend some time to sit down and pray through something, go ahead and do that.
But let's make this a time when we connect with God together as a spiritual family and invite
him to do his work in us. So God, we invite you into this time as we meet with you, as we respond
to you. Lord, we draw our hearts together with you in worship from all the different backgrounds
represented in this room. Lord, build us up as this spiritual family. Even meet each of us in
the personal things that you're speaking to us about and that we're struggling with,
but draw every eye to yourself as we worship you together.